My name's Conan Edogawa!
اسمي إيدوغاوا كونان
High school student Shinichi was forced to take a drug that shrunk him.
أُجبر طالب الثانوية كودو شينتشي على تجرّع عقار قلص جسده
Although smaller, my mind remains that of a sharp detective!
،رغم أنّي أصبحت أصغر !لا يزال عقلي عقل مُتحرٍّ عظيم
Today's case is a code! A deep meaning behind regular numbers!
!قضيّة اليوم شفرة! معنى عميق وراء أرقام عادية
I'll have to change my way of looking at things!
سيكون عليّ تغيير منظوري للأشياء
There's always only one truth!
!والحقيقة واحدة دوماً
The Mysterious Sniper Message Case.
قضيّة رسالة القناص الغامضة
There's some! Now!
!هناك سمك! الآن
Got 'em!
!فعلتُها
They got away again...
...هربت مجدداً
We sure caught a lot!
اصطدنا الكثير
Yeah...
أجل
Genta-kun was right-- this is a good spot for fishing!
كان غينتا-كن محقاً، هذا موقع مثاليّ للصيد
I'm hungry. What time is it?
أشعر بالجوع، ما الوقت الآن؟
It's exactly 1:00. What do you say we have lunch?
إنّها تمام الواحدة ظهراً، هل نتناول الغداء؟
Hey, what's that?
ما ذاك؟
Looks like a remote-controlled boat.
يبدو قارباً بالتحكم عن بعد
Where's it being controlled from?
من أين يُتحكم به؟
A rifle!
!بندقية
Up there! There are people on the building across the river!
في الأعلى! يوجد أشخاص فوق البناء على !الجانب الآخر للنهر
Come on, Conan! Let me see!
!دعني أرى يا كونان
There's nobody up there...
لا يوجد أحد
Did this guy really shoot it with a rifle?!
!هل أطلق ذاك الرجل ببندقية حقاً؟
Dang! He shot the balloon from way up here?!
مُذهل، أصاب البالون من هذا المكان؟
He's really good if he did!
سيكون بارعاً جاداً إن فعل
Maybe he was doing target practice?
ربما كان يتمرن على القنص
That, or he was being tested...
...أو يُختبر
Tested?
يُختبر؟
Against his own will.
بخلاف إرادته
Against his own will?!
بخلاف إرادته؟
Two other guys were pointing handguns at him!
كان هناك اثنان آخران يصوبان مسدّسات نحوه
You serious?!
صدقاً؟
What are you doing?
ما الذي تفعله؟
Looking for any sort of evidence...
أبحث عن ما قد يكون دليلاً
What's with those numbers?
ما خطب هذه الأرقام؟
I'm guessing it's a message the rifle shooter left for me.
إنّها رسالة تركها صاحب البندقية لي غالباً
Message?
رسالة؟
Yes. He seemed to notice me when I saw him through the binoculars.
أجل، بدا أنّه لاحظني عندما رأيتُه بالمنظار المبكر
But what in the world could these numbers mean?
لكن ما يمكن أن تعنيه هذه الأرقام؟
At any rate, we need to tell Inspector Megure about this!
!علينا إخبار المفتش ميغوري بأيّ حال
Are you certain that he hit it from here?
أأنت واثق أنّه أصاب الهدف من هنا؟
Yeah. I didn't see him shoot, but I saw him holding the rifle.
أجل، لم أره يطلق، لكن رأيته يحمل البندقية
And then you found that calculator left behind?
ثمّ وجدت الآلة الحاسبة التي تركها؟
Say, Inspector.
...حضرة المفتش، أيمكن
Do you think that maybe he was kidnapped and then brought here?
أنّه اُختطف وُجرّ إلى هنا؟
It did look like he was forced to shoot against his own will...
بدا أنّه يطلق رغماً عنه
We haven't received any such reports...
لكن لم نتلق أيّ تقارير مشابهة
And I don't see any signs of them being here, either...
...ولا أرى أيّ علامات على وجوده هنا أيضاً
What? Then look harder! Like across the river, or in it!
!ماذا؟! ابحث بإمعان أكثر إذاً مقابل النهر أو داخله
The bullet has to be there somewhere!
!ستجد الرصاصة في مكان حتماً
Yeah! That radio-controlled boat might be--
...أجل! قد يكون قارب التحكم عن بعد ذاك أيضاً
Unfortunately, this is Golden Week.
نحن في الأسبوع الذهبيّ للأسف
Most of our investigators are out on holiday leave!
الكثير من محققينا في إجازة
But I'll tell you what. I'll at least check out that calculator. How's that?
ما رأيكم بهذا، سأفحص تلك الآلة الحاسبة على الأقل، ما قولك؟
Well, I'll see you later. Give Mori-kun my regards!
أراكم لاحقاً إذاً، أوصلوا تحيّتي لموري-كن
He doesn't believe us one bit!
!لا يصدقنا ذاك المُسن أبداً
"Romantic dream trip aboard the Heisei Expressway"?!
رحلة أحلام عاطفية على متن قطار" هيسي السريع"، يا للهراء
All they did was steal an old photo!
كلّ ما فعلوه هو سرقة صورة قديمة
It's hopeless! I can't figure this out!
!لا جدوى، لا يمكنني حلّها
Of course you can't. There is no message.
بالطبع، لا رسالة هناك
Someone just forgot their calculator, that's all.
نسي أحدهم آلته الحاسبة فقط
I can't believe you called Inspector Megure out there
يا إلهي، لا أصدّق أنك استدعيت المفتش ميغوري
during Golden Week!
!في الأسبوع الذهبي
Dad!
!أبي
Say, if that person really was forced to do target practice
...إن كان ذاك الرجل مُجبراً على تمرين قنص حقاً
and then left you a message,
،وترك لك رسالة
all I can think of is...
...فما يمكنني التفكير به
The time or place where the real shooting will take place,
،الزمان والمكان اللّذان سيجري فيهما القنص الحقيقيّ
or the victim's name...
...أو اسم الضحيّة
Or a hint about where he's being held.
أو ربما تلميح لمكان احتجازه
People play code games on their pagers all the time! Number games!
يلعب الناس ألعاب شفرات على !أجهزة إشعارهم طوال الوقت! ألعاب أرقام
So since 3135134 can also be read as a couple of Japanese names,
بما أنّ 3135134 يمكن أن تُقرأ كأسماء يابانية
that means the victims are going to be 31-san and 51-san?
فالضحيّتان سيكونان 31-سان و51-سان؟
Sure, whatever.
أجل، أيّاً يكن
Say, 162 might be an apartment or hotel room number!
اسمع، قد تكون 162 رقم شقّة أو غرفة فندق
Or maybe a road?
أو ربما طريق
Like Route 162, you know?!
مثل الطريق 162
So then what's the 3135134 stand for?
ما الذي ترمز له 3135134 إذاً؟
Maybe it was to camouflage the 162
ربما كانت تغطيةً على 162
in case the bad guys found the calculator.
.في حال وجد المختطفون الآلة الحاسبة
I see. Come to think of it, the river was shaped like a road...
...فهمت، كان شكل النهر كشكل طريق بالتفكير في الأمر
And the flow of the river resembles a flow of cars.
وسيله يشبه سيل السيّارات
Route 162...
...الطريق 162
Kyoto!
!كيوتو
Too far. It would at least have to be in the Tokyo region.
بعيد جدّاً، يجب أن يكون في منطقة طوكيو على الأقل
It would have to be a primary municipal highway.
سيكون خطّاً محلياً سريعاً رئيسياً
Here it is! Saitama Prefectural Route 162!
!ها هو! طريق محافظة سايتاما 162
You found it, Conan-kun!
!وجدته يا كونان-كن
Here it is, Dad! You can take us tomorrow!
!ها هو يا أبي! يمكنك أخذنا غداً
Take you? What now?!
آخذكما؟ ماذا؟
Why did I have to rent a car and drive you around again?!
يا إلهي، لمَ كان عليّ استئجار سيّارة وإيصالكما؟
Because we don't have licenses!
لأنّنا لا نملك رخص قيادة
Hey, he's a detective, right? So why doesn't he have a car of his own?
إنّه مُتحرٍّ، صحيح؟ فلمَ لا يملك سيارته الخاصة؟
He can't afford one!
لا يمكنه شراء واحدة
It sounds like he doesn't usually drive much.
يبدو أنّه لا يقود كثيراً في العادة
We'd better put our seat belts on!
!علينا ربط أحزمة الأمان
Yeah!
!أجل
Hey, you! I'll have you know--
...أنتم! اسمعوا
Keep your eyes on the road!
عينيك على الطريق
The curves are shaped differently.
الالتفاف مختلف الشكل
This isn't the place!
ليس هذا المكان
This isn't it!
ولا هذا
This isn't it either!
ليس هذا أيضاً
Doesn't look like this is it either...
لا يبدو أنّه هذا أيضاً
This isn't it.
ليس هذا
Why don't you give up already?
استسلموا فقط
You're crazy if you think the shape of the river will match a street.
ليس من العقل أن تعتقدوا أن يطابق شكل نهرٍ شارعاً
What? You were the one who said the river flowed like a flow of cars!
ماذا؟ كنتَ من قال أنّ سيل النهر !يشبه سيل السيّارات
Did I now?
أفعلت؟
No more curves to check, I take it?
لم تبق أيّ التفافات لتفقدها، صحيح؟
I'll just turn around up here and--
...سأنعطف هنا و
Under construction...
قيد الإنشاء
Stop the car!
!توقف! توقف
Conan-kun?
كونان-كن؟
Aha!
!فهمت
This building's on Route 162 too!
!هذا البناء على الطريق 162 أيضاً
This is the place!
!هذا هو المكان
You're right!
!معك حق
It's definitely it!
!هو حتماً
Way to go, Conan!
!أحسنت يا كونان
What? You found it?!
!ما الخطب؟ وجدتموه؟
Conan-kun wants you to tell Inspector Megure.
يريد منك كونان-كن أن تخبر المفتش ميغوري
Why me?
لمَ أنا؟
Because you have a good track record, plus he trusts you!
!لأنّ لديك سجّل إنجازات، كما يثق بك
A good track record? You sure know about hard-to-understand things!
!سجّل إنجازات؟ تعرف الأشياء معقدة الفهم حقاً
Oh well, guess I'll give him a ring!
!حسناً، لعلّي سأعطيه اتصالاً
Megure here.
أجل، معك ميغوري
Oh, Mori-kun! Perfect timing!
!موري-كن! توقيت ممتاز
Come to the police headquarters right away!
!تعال لمركز الشرطة فوراً
And bring Conan-kun with you!
!كما اجلب كونان-كن معك
There is only one reason why I've asked you to come here.
هناك سبب واحد لدعوتي لكم هنا
We've learned that one of our officers on vacation and his girlfriend
عرفنا أنّ أحد ضبّاطنا الخارجين في عطلة وحبيبته
have gone missing.
قد اختفيا
This man.
إنّه هذا الرجل
This is the guy, Inspector!
!إنّه هو سيّدي المفتش
I thought so.
كما ظننت
The fingerprints on the calculator matched his own when we checked.
تطابقت بصماته مع التي على الآلة الحاسبة عندما أجرينا فحصاً
His name is Koichi Yamabe.
اسمه يامابي كويتشي
He used to be an Olympic marksman.
كان قنّاصاً أولمبياً في السابق
A marksman?!
قنّاص؟
The kidnappers probably took Yamabe and his girlfriend, Eri-san,
اختطفه المجرمون مع حبيبته إيري-سان غالباً
and are threatening to kill her if he doesn't shoot someone for them.
ويهددونه بقتلها إلم يقنص أحداً لهم
So what Conan-kun and the others saw was target practice for that?
ما رآه كونان-كن والبقية كان تمريناً لذلك؟
Looks like your deductions hit the mark!
يبدو أنّ تحليلك أصاب عين الحقيقة
But our hands are still tied since we don't know the most important facts:
لكن لا تزال أيدينا مقيدة بما أننا نجهل أهم حقيقة
when and where it will happen...
ألا وهي موعد ومكان القنص
We know where!
!نحن... نعرف المكان
Come again?!
!ماذا؟
Yes, it's very similar, indeed.
أجل، إنّه يشبهه فعلاً
It looks like this is the place. Excellent work!
يبدو أنّه المكان، بلاء حسن يا صغار
Um, don't forget that I was the one who drove them here!
!لا تنس أنّي من قادهم إلى هنا
But we still don't know when the attack will be...
...لكن لا نزال نجهل موعد الهجوم
Yes, that's too bad...
...أجل، هذا مؤسف
It was around 1 pm when the balloon burst, right?
انفجر البالون عند الواحدة ظهراً تقريباً، صحيح؟
Is that so? Then 1:00 must be the time of the attack!
هكذا إذاً، سيكون الواحدة ظهراً !موعد الهجوم إذاً
But on what day?
لكن أيّ يوم؟
They're keeping two people captive! They don't have time to waste!
إنّهم يحتجزون شخصين، لا وقت لهم ليهدروه
The sniper attack will probably be tomorrow!
!ستجري عمليّة القنص غداً غالباً
Good thinking, Mori-kun!
!تفكير ممتاز يا موري-كن
Let's make preparations at once!
!لنقم بالتجهيزات فوراً
What's the matter, Conan-kun?
ما الخطب يا كونان-كن؟
Oh, nothing...
لا شيء
Does this 162 really refer to Route 162?
هل ترمز 162 هذه للطريق 162 حقاً؟
If it were me, I would make sure to put the place and time in the message...
لو كنت محله، لأضفت المكان والموعد في الرسالة بلا شك
Which means...
...مما يعني
No...
كلا
No matter how I look at it, the 3135134 still makes no sense!
كيفما نظرت لها، تبقى 3135134 مستعصية الفهم
Alright now. Don't make a move until I give the order.
حسناً، لا تقوموا بأيّ حركة حتى أعطي الأمر
Roger that!
!عُلِم
We have police snipers and a helicopter on standby at the river.
لدينا قنّاصو شرطة ومروحية على استعداد عند النهر
All preparations are complete.
التجهيزات مكتملة
If the sniper's going to strike at 1:00,
،إن كان القنص سيقع عند الواحدة
then the criminals should appear by 12:00 at the latest.
فسيأتي المجرمون عند 12:00 بأبعد الاحتمالات
One hour left...
...تبقت ساعة
But would you mind explaining why--
...لكن هلّا وضحت
They insisted on coming along!
!أصرّوا على القدوم
You guys aren't to leave this van!
!أنتم! إيّاكم ومغادرة السيارة
Well?!
!ردّكم؟
We know!
!نعرف
My ears...
...أ-أذناي
Thirty minutes left...
تبقت 30 دقيقة
Something's not right! Why aren't they showing up?!
هناك خطبٌ ما، لمَ لا يظهرون؟
Maybe Conan-kun is wrong?
لعلّ استنتاج كونان-كن كان خاطئاً
What?!
!ماذا؟
Of course he isn't!
!بالطبع لا
No, that has to be it!
!بل معه حق
It was a mistake to listen to some stupid kid!
!كان الاستماع لكلام طفل غلطة بالأصل
Dad!
!أبي
Let's see...
...لنرَ
It was 3135134162, right?
كانت 3135134162، صحيح؟
3, 1, 3, 5, 1, 3, 4...
...ثلاثة، واحد، ثلاثة، خمسة، واحد، ثلاثة، أربعة
Mitsuhiko! Let me see that!
!ميتسوهيكو! أعطني إيّاها
Okay...
حسناَ
That's it! Now I see!
!فهمت! هكذا إذاَ
You have it upside-down, Conan-kun...
أنت تقلبها يا كونان-كن
Oh, wow!
!أجل
You can read the numbers even when you flip the calculator over! Cool!
يمكنك قراءة الأرقام حتى عندما !تقلب الآلة الحاسبة! غريب
What nonsense is this now?
ما الهراء الذي تقوله؟
See! 162 becomes 291!
!انظر! 162 تصبح 291
And the rest looks like English letters!
والبقية كأنّها أحرف إنجليزية
Let me see that.
دعني أرى
291, Heisei E...
‏291، هيسي إي
They are readable...
إنّها تُقرأ حقاً
Heisei E? Wait, I could swear I've seen that somewhere before...
...هيسي إي؟ لحظة، رأيتُ ذلك قبلاً
It was in the magazine you were looking at yesterday!
كان في المجلة التي كنت تنظر لها بالأمس
The Heisei Express!
!قطار هيسي السريع
Wait, then that means this message was meant to be read upside-down!
لحظة، إن كان يُفترض أن تُقرأ هذه الرسالة مقلوبة من البداية
Meaning that the 162 actually means the 29th at 1:00!
فـ 162 تعني التاسع والعشرين عند 1:00
What?!
!ماذا؟
Yamabe-san must have realized this upside-down trick
أدرك يامابي-سان حيلة القلب هذه
where he was being held
...وهو معتقل غالباً وحاول ترك
and tried to leave us this message when he got the chance!
!هذه الرسالة عندما سنحت له هذه الفرصة
Inspector! Hurry! The helicopter!
!سيّدي المفتش! بسرعة! المروحية
Oh, right!
!أجل، صحيح
Heisei Express will be departing from Platform 2 shortly.
سيغادر قطار هيسي السريع الرصيف الثاني قريباً
Thank you!
شكراً جزيلاً
Excuse me!
المعذرة
Yes?
أجل؟
Sit down before the train starts, Daddy!
!اجلس قبل تحرك القطار يا أبي
Ok, I will...
حسناً، سأفعل
It's going just as we planned.
الأمور تجري وفق الخطة
He's sitting in the very front of the first car!
إنّه جالس في مقدمة العربة الأمامية
It's time.
حان الوقت
Eh?! Don't tell me he's--
...ماذا؟! أيمكن أنه
What? When did you get in here?!
!ماذا؟! متى دخلت؟
It doesn't matter! We won't make it in time if we don't hurry!
!لا يهم! لن نصل في الوقت إلم نسرع
Fine, whatever. Put this on!
!ليس باليد حيلة، ارتد هذه
Too big!
!كبيرة
There's the Kanetsu Line!
!إنّه خطّ كانيتسو
Okay! Follow the tracks north!
!حسنٌ، اتبع السكّة شمالاً
Three minutes left...
...تبقت 3 دقائق
We still haven't found a curve that looks like the river!
لم نجد التفافاً شبيهاً بالنهر بعد
Here it comes.
أتى
Try any funny business and the girl's dead.
تفهم، صحيح؟ إن أقدمت على أمر غريب فستفقد الفتاة حياتها
One minute left!
تبقت دقيقة
Inspector! There!
!سيّدي المفتش! هناك
There they are! Get us lower!
!ها هم! اهبط أكثر
What the...?
!ما-ماذا؟
Who cares! Just shoot it down!
!لا تهتم! أطلق عليهم
Bastard!
!وغد
Stop or she's dead!
!توقف وإلّا ستلقى حتفها
Don't shoot! You might hit Yamabe!
!لا تطلق! قد تصيب يامابي
Yes, sir!
!حاضر
There's no wind! The helicopter's speed is 5 meters per second!
لا رياح، سرعة المروحية 5 أمتار في الثانية
Medium setting should do the trick!
الضبط المتوسط سيفي بالغرض
Distance: 30 meters!
المسافة: 30 متراً
Go!
!انطلقي
Got 'im!
!أصبته
What're you doing?! That's dangerous!
!ما الذي تفعله؟! هذا خطر
Damn it!
!اللعنة
Damn you!
!تبّاً لك
It's all over! Give yourself up!
!انتهى الأمر! استسلم
Koichi-san!
!كويتشي-سان
Eri!
إيري
What a stroke of luck that this helmet just happened to hit him!
إصابة الخوذة له كانت ضربة حظّ حقاً
Here you are. Don't drop it on the way back, now!
!خذ، لا تسقطها ثانيةً في طريق العودة
I won't!
!أجل
Man, was that close...
...يا إلهي، كان ذلك وشيكاً
You're okay! That's great!
!أنت بخير! حمداً لله
Hey, Conan! That wasn't fair, you get all the fun!
!كونان! لم يكن ذلك منصفاً !أخذت كلّ المتعة
It isn't nice to hog all the glory!
ليس لطيفاً أن تستحوذ على كلّ المجد
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Sorry!
!آسف
Huh?
ماذا؟
Conan! No more sneaking off without permission!
!كونان! يكفي تسللاً دون إذن
He got you that time!
!أصابك هذه المرة
Why you little...
!أنت
The men we arrested were former members of the Oni Tora crime ring.
الرجال الذين اُعتقلوا كانوا أعضاء سابقين في حلقة أوني تورا الإجرامية
Last year, the leader and various high-ranking officials in the ring
سجنَ مدّعٍ عام بارع العام الماضي
were all put behind bars by a skilled public prosecutor.
القائدَ وعدّة مسؤولين رفيعي المستوى في حلقتهم
The remaining members were forced to disband.
أُجبر بقية الأعضاء على الانفصال
So it was that prosecutor they were after?
كانوا يستهدفون ذاك المدّعي إذاً؟
He was on his way home from a trip with his family.
كان في عودته من رحلة مع عائلته
Revenge was their motive.
الانتقام كان دافعهم
But you did a spectacular job, Mori-kun!
!لكن كان بلاؤك مذهلاً يا موري-كن
I don't think I did...
...حسناً، لا أظن أنّي
...that bad, myself!
!قصّرت في عملي
They're acting like he solved it all by himself.
يتصرف كأنّه حلّ القضية بنفسه
But I'm sure he'll take us on vacation somewhere now!
لكن سيأخذنا الآن في عطلة !لمكان ما حتماً
Where would you want to go, Conan-kun?
أين تريد الذهاب يا كونان-كن؟
That's easy! An amusement park!
!ذلك سهل! حديقة الملاهي
Boy, it sure is hard to constantly act like a kid!
...يا إلهي، من العسير التصرف كطفل دوماً
It's a dead body!
!إنها جثّة
It's disappeared!
!ليست هنا
That's impossible!
مستحيل
Let's go, everyone.
لنغادر جميعاً
Wait, Inspector! We really saw--
...انتظر سيّدي المفتش! رأينا حقاً
I was a fool to believe you!
كنتُ أحمق للوثوق بكم
No, the body is here!
كلا، الجثّة هنا
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
The Missing Corpse Murder.
جريمة قتل الجثّة المفقودة
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Answering Machine Phone.
هاتف جهاز ردّ آلي